Thomas E. Kendig

48001 Leontine Court Fremont, CA 94539 (510) 657-2579 tom.kendig@kendig.net

System Administrator and Computer Support Tools Specialist

Able to configuring computers, networks and software and writing code as small single applications or as a part of large parallel code development projects. Providing product builds for release and project source archiving and project revision control.

Programming responsibility included developing and maintaining robot to tester communications and control with a dynamically loadable library (.dll) under Microsoft .net and a shared object (.so) under UNIX. This project was over 100K lines of code and was ported across four computer operating systems.

The success of the software project depended on the extensive documentation (Frame/HTML) and ftp site distribution to customers all over the world.

Professional Skills

Software OS and Tools

.Net/Visual Studio/Codecenter Windows XP/NT SourceSafe/make/ClearCase/SCCS UNIX/Solaris/SunOS Framemaker/PDF DNS/NFS Serial (RS232), IEEE488 (GPIB) communications National Instruments GPIB analyzer UNIX system administration Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Power Point)

Computer Languages

C/C++ PASCAL bourne/csh shell scripts SQL/RPL LISP Modula-2, PL/1, FORTRAN

Engineering Applications

Communications Driver development

Real-Time Programming

Data processing (ASCII & STDF)

Software Test Procedures

VLSI Pattern Conversion

Circuit Testing

VLSI testing

Semiconductor Processing

Thomas E. Kendig

48001 Leontine Ct Fremont, CA 94539 (510) 657-2579 tom.kendig@kendig.net

WORK HISTORY

Software Engineer – Credence Systems Corp., Fremont, CA 1991-1992 & 1996-2005

- Assist customers in automation software install and test on their production floor.
- Ported a Graphical User Interface from a SUN 3 based architecture to a SPARC architecture. This included resolving porting problems such as data structure incompatibility in RPC packets and SunView programming errors.
- Improved a custom software build process that made extensive and unusual use of the utilities make and SCCS.

UNIX System Administrator – Landis & Gyr Energy Management, San Jose, CA 1995

- Organized company UNIX resources to effectively use existing computing communications and networking resources to improve uptime.
- Developed and maintained backups, namespace, email and networking strategy.

Configuration Management Specialist – TRW Financial Systems, Oakland, CA1994-1995

- Support and maintain configuration management and UNIX tools for larges software development project.
- Track configuration assistance incidents and provide solutions for configuration and system administration.

Customer Support Engineer – TeamOne Systems Inc., Sunnyvale, CA 1992-1994

- Provided 800 number customer support for configuration management software. TeamOne's system is a kernel based file system. Support entails knowing UNIX file systems, NFS and system administration.
- Developed call tracking software package facilitating call follow up and producing statistical measurements on incoming call servicing.

EDUCATION

Carnegie-Mellon University, PGH, PA

BS in Mathematics, emphasis in CS and EE